<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Command-line tool on sdmx-dl</title>
    <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Command-line tool on sdmx-dl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/installation/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Automatic installation Manual installation Zero installation Troubleshooting Requirements sdmx-dl CLI runs on any operating systems that support the Java VM (Virtual Machine) such as Microsoft Windows, Solaris OS, Apple macOS, Ubuntu and other various Linux distributions.
It requires a Java SE Runtime Environment (JRE) version 8 or later to run on such as OpenJDK. You can download a free, binary distribution of the OpenJDK at one of the following provider: Zulu JDK, Adoptium, Amazon Corretto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/configuration/</guid>
      <description>sdmx-dl CLI is designed to work out-of-the-box but can be configured if needed by using several properties files.
Properties files Command options Execution properties Troubleshooting Properties files The properties files are just text files that contains a list of key-value pairs.
All these files are named sdmx-dl.properties and are located in 3 different folders which are parsed in a specific order to define a scope:
SYSTEM: the installation folder (where the binary is located) GLOBAL: the user profile folder (%userprofile% on Windows) LOCAL: the execution folder (where the CLI is called) Each of these scopes overwrites properties defined in the previous scope; for example, properties in execution folder overrides those in user profile folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usage</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/usage/</guid>
      <description>By default, all commands print the result on the standard output.
Most commands produce RFC4180 compliant CSV content.
Command arguments are composed of options and positional parameters. Options have a name, positional parameters are usually the values that follow the options, but they may be mixed. The general pattern is:
sdmx-dl fetch data ECB EXR M.CHF.EUR.SP00.A -o chf.csv command parameters options All commands share the following options:
-h, --help - Show an help message and exit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/options/</guid>
      <description>An option has the following caracteristics:
it has a name prefixed by two hyphens (e.g. --version). it may have a shortcut prefixed by one hyphen (e.g. -h is a shortcut of --help). it is case-sensitive Shortcuts can be grouped behind one hyphen (e.g. -vh is equivalent to -v -h).
The options default values are system-independent.
Common General-purpose options used by various commands.
Name Shortcut Parameter Description --verbose -v - Enable verbose mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data types</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/datatypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/datatypes/</guid>
      <description>Common file encoding char string locale datetime The date-time format is ISO-8601.
number A number is a numeric value.
Format: depends on the locale and number pattern.
Note: The number format provider has been changed in JDK9 (see JEP252) so the formatting might be different when using an old JDK. For example, NaN value (aka &amp;ldquo;not-a-number&amp;rdquo;) is represented by NaN in JDK9+ but was represented by U+FFFD REPLACEMENT CHARACTER in JDK8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nbbrd.github.io/sdmx-dl/docs/develop/cli/examples/</guid>
      <description>Download monthly (M) exchange rates (EXR) of Swiss franc (CHF) from the European Central Bank (ECB) sdmx-dl fetch data ECB EXR M.CHF.EUR.SP00.A Same as 1 with saving into a file sdmx-dl fetch data ECB EXR M.CHF.EUR.SP00.A -o filename.csv Same as 1 with saving into a compressed file sdmx-dl fetch data ECB EXR M.CHF.EUR.SP00.A -o filename.csv.gz -z Same as 1 with displaying as human-readable table (PowerShell example) sdmx-dl fetch data ECB EXR M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
